UK / French / Lebanese nationalities Currently based in London, United Kingdom thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

# Tech Lead / Lead Software Engineer

# Profile

I am a software engineer with 15 years of experience building tech solutions across several industries with a strong entrepreneurial focus. I am equally comfortable with hands-on delivery (i.e. writing code) and managing engineering teams (i.e. helping other developers write code). I help organisations embrace new technologies to solve challenging real-world problems and launch successful products that customers love.

# Work experience

#### Senior Software Engineer (contract based), July 2019 to present

- → **Bulb Energy,** London, United Kingdom Mar. 2022 to Nov. 2022 (<u>bulb.co.uk</u>)

  Building new features for rolling out electric smart meters installations across the business.

  <u>Technology:</u> TypeScript, Node.js, Kubernetes, Docker, GCP, BigQuery, Postgres, Terraform
- → **ApprenticeFS**, Remote Sept. to Dec. 2021 (apprentice.io)

  Building new features for an intelligent pharmaceutical manufacturing execution system SaaS platform.

  <u>Technology:</u> TypeScript, Node.js, Docker, Angular12, MongoDB, NX, AWS, Elasticsearch.
- → Conde Nast, Remote Mar. to Sept. 2021 (condenast.com)

  Building and Improving a content migration tool for Conde Nast's in-house engineering teams.

  Building APIs and tools automating content migration for 50 publications to a new tech stack.

  Technology: Node.js, TypeScript, GraphQL, Express, React, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, CircleCl, OAuth
- → **Progressive Content,** Remote Sept. 2020 to Feb. 2021 (progressivecontent.com)

  Building a microservices backend for a UK-based banking client's content marketing CMS.

  <u>Technology:</u> Serverless (Lambda), TypeScript, GraphQL, Node.js, Docker, Jenkins, AWS, Elasticsearch.
- → **AND Digital,** London, United Kingdom July 2019 to April 2020 (and.digital)

  Leading a development team part of a cloud transformation project for a UK insurance client.

  Managing a team of 4 developers. Writing code for replatforming an end-user web application. Integrating with 3rd party back-office services (both REST and SOAP). Refining user stories. Code reviews.

  <u>Technology:</u> Serverless, TypeScript, Express, Node.js, React, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, REST, SOAP.

#### **Tech Advisor** for an early-stage startup

Emani.io, London, United Kingdom - Since November 2021 (emani.io)

Hiring an engineering team, building product road map, tech strategy and delivering the core product.

#### Coach / Mentor, since 2017

Mentoring for the tech lead curriculum for the primary french online education platform <a href="Open Classrooms">Open Classrooms</a>

#### **Head of Engineering** for a health-tech startup

Skin Analytics, London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (skin-analytics.com)

- → Responsible for clients, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures

  Hiring and leading technical team (8 members between UK and Poland). Managing applications, cloud infrastructure and releases. Defining roadmaps and priorities and scoping new requirements. Writing code. Day to day management, code reviews and testing. Delivered a Software as a Medical Device commercial API.
- → <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, Serverless (Lambda), TypeScript, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Ansible.

Technical Lead for an international online media publishing group

Jamie Oliver, London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (<u>jamieoliver.com</u>)

Lead a migration from a legacy SOAP CRM to a microservices architecture. Managing contractors.

<u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

## Team Leader / Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components

  Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local startups among the most repressive regimes. Leading on delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

  Overseeing the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 5 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Focus on scalability & security.

Technology: Node.js, PHP (Laravel), WordPress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

.

#### Web Application Engineer for an international NGO

Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - Mar. 2009 to Mar. 2015 (internews.org)

→ Online freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Deployment and monitoring of secure hosting & video platforms. Facilitating training & trainers: website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).

<u>Technology</u>: Drupal, WordPress, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Vagrant, Nginx, Linux administration

**Software Engineer** for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (hellotipi.com)

Technology: MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg, Debian, Linux administration

.

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in the two major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs.

.

**Junior Software Engineer** for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (<u>valeo.com</u>) Designed & implemented tools for course support creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

#### Education

# MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (<u>esiea.fr</u>) → *Graduated with first class honours*.

### **Foreign languages**

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner

## **Hobbies**

Collecting records (LPs), mostly nerdy noisy music. <u>Photography</u> (film and digital). Part of the media team of a <u>non-league fan-owned football club</u> in East London.